Well, I have to tell you that I'm a little bit sad.
솔직히 말하면 좀 슬퍼요 비트 박스요
This is the beginning of the beginning of the end.
이건 종말의 시작의 시작이에요
It's the beginning of our last time together.
마지막 시간이 시작됐어요
The final.
결승전요
The end of the finale.
피날레의 끝이죠
The conclusion of our eight week voyage.
8주간의 항해가 이렇게 끝났네요
To take you from the very beginning to LLM mastery.
초기부터 LLM 마스터까지 가르쳐 드리죠
And what a fitting conclusion it should hopefully be.
아주 적절한 결론이죠
I realize I maybe oversold some of the excitement that was in store, but I do hope that you shared
제가 너무 기대감을 부풀린 것 같지만 그 기대감을 저와 공유하셨으면
some of it with me, that you also enjoyed this project and that you're ready for the last stages.
해요 이 프로젝트를 즐기셨고 마지막 단계로 갈 준비가 되셨죠
So what you can do now is so much to it that I couldn't possibly, possibly do it.
지금 할 수 있는 건 제가 할 수 없는 거예요
The injustice of squeezing it into three bullets.
총알 세 발로 쪼개다니 불공평해요
So it now dominates most of this page.
그래서 이 페이지 대부분을 차지하고 있죠
And obviously what's in store for us today is to get to the top of the mountain and complete the mastering
오늘 우리는 정상에 올라서 인공지능과 LLM 공학에 통달해야 합니다
of AI and engineering and LLM engineering, the missing piece for us, if we look at our Agentic AI
에이전틱 인공지능 솔루션을 보면 우리가 놓친 부분이 있습니다 각각의 요소를
solution, we covered each of these different pieces, and perhaps the one that we hadn't yet completely
다뤘는데 자율성을 갖는다는 부분에서 아직 미흡했던 부분이
ticked the box of was having autonomy.
있죠
We have got memory.
메모리가 있어요
We've in a sense, although there's not much point in having memory if it doesn't, if it only runs
어떤 면에선 메모리를 갖는 게 별 의미가 없어요 한 번만 실행한다면요
So yeah, we really need to pull all of this together and have it into a process that is running, and
네, 이 모든 걸 함께 끌어모아 실행 중인 프로세스에 넣어야 해요 그래야 여러분이
so that you'll be able to kick something off and then just go away and get on with your daily life and
뭔가를 시작하고 그냥 가서 일상을 보낼 수 있죠 문자도 받고요
Push notified from time to time as deals come up on the internet that seem worthy of your attention.
인터넷에 관심 가질 만한 거래가 올라오면 가끔씩 알려주세요
Uh, and so this one more time was the agentic workflows that we had put together.
에이전틱 워크플로를 다시 한 번 살펴봤어요
And of course, we built everything in red in one session when we we built out our, our prices, including
한 세션에서 모든 것을 빨간색으로 설정했습니다. Modal과 크로마 검색을
the specialist pricing that calls out to modal and the frontier processor that uses our chroma lookup.
이용한 프론티어 프로세서의 전문가 가격도 포함해서요.
Um, and then we built an ensemble that takes the weighted average of them all.
그리고 모든 참가자의 평균을 반영하는 앙상블을 만들었어요
Uh, and we then assembled it together with our scanner and our messaging and planning so that we'd
스캐너로 정보를 수집하고 메시지를 보내고 계획을 세워서 모든 걸 하나로
have everything together.
모았어요
And then last time we used something that was fancily called an agent framework, but was nothing more
그리고 마지막으로 사용했던 것은 에이전트 프레임워크라는 것이었는데 파이썬 을 이용해서
than a Python script to glue everything together.
모든 것을 하나로 연결했어요
And of course you can, as I say, get agent frameworks through through various off the shelf frameworks.
그리고 물론 다양한 규격 프레임워크를 통해 에이전트 프레임워크를 get 할 수 있어요
But most of what they're doing is exactly what we did ourselves, uh, through simple Python.
하지만 대부분의 작업은 저희가 심플 파이썬 으로 했던 것과 동일해요
All right.
좋아요
So what remains, what remains is for us to go back with one last time to JupyterLab, where we will
이제 남은 건 마지막으로 유피터랩으로 돌아가는 겁니다 제
start playing with my old friend Gradio.
오랜 친구 그라디오와 함께요
Uh, we will be right there.
금방 갈게요